usborne.com 2019-10-14

# Privacy | Usborne Websites

This Privacy Policy applies to the Usborne Children’s Books website at www.usborne.com, including the Usborne Quicklinks website at [www.usborne.com/quicklinks](http://www.usborne.com/quicklinks) (the Usborne Website).

Your personal information is important to us. We highlight below matters relating to your information that you should be aware of.

We will endeavour to take all due care to protect this information, in accordance with the applicable Data Protection legislation from time to time, for the purposes of which Usborne Publishing is the data controller.

### What personal information do we collect?

If you contact us with an enquiry, we collect from you essential contact details (your name, e-mail address, phone number and your country) in order to handle your enquiry. Your personal details will not be used for any other purposes.

If you wish to order any of our goods online, we will ask you to provide the personal information that we need for this purpose (your name, e-mail address, phone number, delivery address, and your credit or debit card number and bank details).

All payment transactions are run through the Verifone secure payment system (for further see details see <https://www.verifone.com/legal>), for which purposes Verifone is our data processor. We do not store any card details but can access transaction records to confirm payments.

### Why do we process your information?

If you contact us with an enquiry, we will process the personal information that you provide, or we collect from you, including your name, e-mail address, phone number and your country, on the basis that it is necessary for the legitimate interests we have in promoting Usborne Publishing and the sale of its goods, and does not prejudice or harm your rights and freedoms.

If you order goods from us, we will process your personal information on the basis that it is necessary to do so for the performance of the contract that we enter into with you, and to manage your account with us.

If you sign up to our Usborne Newsletter, we will provide your with news of details of offers and other opportunities , including by post or by email, and on the basis that it is necessary for the legitimate interests we have in promoting Usborne Publishing and the sale of its goods (as described above).  We will only contact you in this way if you agree to opt-in. Details of how to do so, and how to opt-out of receiving details of such offers, are on relevant pages of the Usborne Website, or will be in the forms you complete and/or the emails you receive from us.

### Competitions

In order for you to participate in our competitions or for us to send you free materials such as posters, badges and bookmarks, we ask you to provide us with personal information, such as your name, email address, age and postal address.  We will process your personal information on the basis that it is necessary for the legitimate interests we have in promoting Usborne Publishing and the sale of its goods (as described above).  After sending you materials or notifying you that you have won a competition, your personal information will not be retained on our files, unless you have indicated that you would like to receive the Usborne email newsletter. You can unsubscribe from the newsletter email at any time by following the instructions on the Usborne Website, or by writing to the address at the end of this Privacy Policy, and your details will be removed from our files.

### Children

If you are under 18, please make sure that you obtain your parent/guardian's permission before you provide your personal information to the Usborne Website.

Children under the age of 13 must ask permission of an adult before entering a competition or sending any personal information. If you are the parent or guardian of a child under 13, we may process limited personal data about you so you can give consent for the child to enter a competition. We may use your contact details to communicate with you about the child’s account or use of our services.

### Usborne apps

Usborne apps do not collect any information about how children use the app and there are no in-app purchases. There are no links to external websites from within the apps.

### Who do we share your information with?

We may disclose your personal data if we need to do so in order to comply with any legal or regulatory obligation or request, or where we have a legitimate interest in doing so, such as in order to enforce or apply our contract, to investigate potential breaches, or to protect the rights, property or safety of the Company or others. This may include exchanging information with other companies and organisations for the purposes of fraud protection and credit risk reduction.

Except as set out above, we will never sell, distribute or disclose any of your personal information (except anonymous aggregate information) with any third party without your express consent.

In order to provide some of our services, we may use the input of third party providers situated in countries outside Europe (such as the USA) that do not always have the same standards of Data Protection laws as the UK. However, we will ensure that contractual or other safeguards are in place to ensure that your information is adequately protected, and that enforceable rights and effective legal remedies are available for data subjects.

For our Usborne Newsletter (and related purposes) we use MailChimp, which participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Their privacy policy is available at [https://mailchimp.com/legal/privacy](https://protect-eu.mimecast.com/s/OdxFCKrPKtz448TkGQRQ?domain=mailchimp.com).

### How long do we keep personal information for?

If you contact us with an enquiry but do not enter into a contract with us, we will normally delete your personal data after six months. If you order any of our goods online, we normally retain contract information (including personal data) for six years after the end of the relevant contract, in case issues arise after the termination of the contract.

In certain case, it may not be physically possible to delete certain data (for instance, where it is stored on a secure external server), in which case we will take appropriate steps to ensure that it is not available for re-use or disclosure to third parties.

### Your rights as a data subject

As a data subject you have certain legal rights including:

  * The right to access the personal data held about you
  * The right to ask us not to process your personal data for marketing purposes
  * The right to withdraw at any time any consent you have given to receive marketing material from us
  * The right to ask us to rectify inaccurate personal data about you
  * The right to ask for the restriction of personal data concerning yourself that is inaccurate, unlawfully processed, or no longer required
  * The right to ask for the erasure of personal data concerning yourself where processing is no longer necessary, or the legitimate interests we have in processing your personal data are overridden by your interests, rights and freedoms as the data subject
  * The right to make a complaint to the supervisory authority (the Information Commissioner’s Office)

### Cookies

Cookies are text files that websites use to store information on your computer. The Usborne Website uses "session cookies" and anonymous "analytic" cookies to support the navigation system of this website while you are browsing.

We use standard cookies to save information that may be helpful for your computer to remember, and to ensure that we give you the best experience on our website. For example, on the Usborne Children’s Books website we save your chosen territory so you do not have to reset it every time you visit. We also use standard cookies to "save" the content of your shopping basket for up to 14 days, in case you are interrupted while browsing. No personal details are collected or stored at any time through the use of cookies. 

Our website uses Google Analytics, a service that helps us plan and design our website. Google Analytics places a cookie on your computer or device and transmits website traffic data to Google servers in the United States. Google Analytics does not identify individual users and we do not store any personally identifiable information within Google Analytics. You can visit the Google website to find out more about their [privacy policy](https://support.google.com/analytics/answer/6004245?hl=en).

Apart from the information described in this Privacy Policy, we do not maintain any personal information obtained from users through the Usborne Website in a retrievable form.

You can find out more about cookies on the  _[AboutCookies.org](http://www.aboutcookies.org/)_  website, including how to decline or remove them. However, if you do not accept cookies from Usborne.com you will not be able to purchase any books from our website.

### Further information

In case of questions, comments or requests regarding our use of your personal information, please contact us by email to: [privacy@usborne.co.uk](mailto:privacy@usborne.co.uk), or write to us at the following address:

Usborne Publishing,   
83-85 Saffron Hill,   
London,   
EC1N 8RT.

Usborne Publishing Limited is registered in England and Wales.   
Registered number 01124359.   
Registered office: 83-85 Saffron Hill, London, EC1N 8RT.
